# NATHAN ELMORE

(406) 672 - 4249 | Billings, MT | elmore.nathan@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

A seasoned software engineer with 12 years of experience known for consistently delivering results. A proven ability to quickly adapt and produce valuable solutions with experience in both systems programming and web applications. Demonstrated commitment to creating effective, maintainable software that meets business needs.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Product Engineer – PAI, A Brink's Company | Billings, MT

Jan 2024 - Present

- Lead a feature team that delivers new features and products, maintains legacy code, performs DevOps, and improves the developer tooling.
- Spearheaded an effort to enhance front-end developer experience by transitioning our monolithic architecture to a Vite based monorepo structure. This results in instant feedback instead of 60-second builds, improved linting, easier testing, faster onboarding, and an upgrade path for legacy user interfaces. I collaborated with team members to provide mentorship and learning opportunities throughout the project.
- Led a project that integrated our system with a new wireless provider that significantly reduced monthly data usage costs. My feature team developed tools that save the wireless team hours of time each week and created dashboards that provide insights for better decision making.
- Created an Incident Retrospective process for the development team to reflect on high severity incidents. This leads to actionable plans to prevent future incidents and better responses to incidents.
- Integrated our end of month billing processes with Avalara to conditionally calculate tax of billing items as configured by the finance team, saving them hours of work monthly.
- Foster a culture of continual learning by leading learning sessions that review software books, discuss conference talks, and do coding challenges.
- Both mentor and learn from my feature team with pair and ensemble programming, working with stakeholders and managing projects.

# **Software Developer L2** – PAI, A Brink's Company | Billings, MT

Nov 2020 - Dec 2023

- Collaborate with project stakeholders to identify requirements, design solutions, create new products
  or integrate them into existing products.
- Created a wireless inventory management system that facilitates every step in the inventory process from the initial purchase order to drop shipping to PAI customers. The wireless team can purchase wireless inventory from the manufacturer in China, and track its status as it is produced, shipped, activated and shelved in warehouse ready for sale. It automatically integrates with our ERP and web store so that the inventory is tracked and is drop shipped when purchased. This saves our warehouse operations team from storing, scanning, configuring and shipping thousands of wireless devices each year.
- Designed and implemented a system to automatically import, process, and resolve ATM disputes. This saves the company months of person-hours of work each year, tens of thousands of dollars in technician dispatches and unresolved disputes each month.
- Simplified and standardized a process for creating new file based data feeds with an ETL Pipeline toolset. These tools significantly reduce development time for new data feeds, and simplify operations and deployment.
- Developed a feature that prevents thousands of technician dispatches to ATMs and technical support calls yearly calls by remotely configuring ATMs and automatically identifying and repairing misconfigurations.

- Freed hundreds of GB of storage on our primary production database with an automated process for archiving old transaction data that needs to be stored for compliance.
- Reduced support ticket calls and manual data entry with a reporting tools and a service that tracks issued checks and imports them into our ERP system.

# **Software Engineer** – Shenandoah Solutions, Inc. | Red Lodge, MT

Jan 2012 – Oct 2020

- Collaboratively built a Multi-Aspect Radar System (MARS) with a small team of engineers working on all aspects of system development, including requirements determination, system and software design, hardware configuration, calibration, Linux server administration, in-lab integration and testing, and field testing.
- Developed, tested, and debugged software components for the following: radar scheduling, ADC/DAC boards, Digital I/O, frequency synthesizers, Automatic Identification System (AIS), and other hardware interfaces.
- Modified the MARS software and hardware to operate as a multi-channel digitizer with real time data recording and export over 10 Gb Ethernet on an airborne platform (ADAS).
- Implemented DISA Security Technical Implementation Guides (STIGs) for the MARS and ADAS Red Hat operating systems.
- Wrote hardware and software specification documents for the AN/SPS-73(V)18 surface search radar.
- Performed requirements analysis, wrote design verification tests and factory qualification tests for the AN/SPS-73(V)18 surface search radar.

#### **EDUCATION**

## University of Montana – Master of Science in Computer Science

2010 - 2012

• Thesis on machine learning applied to streaming physiological data to predict human emotion.

# Rocky Mountain College – Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

2006 - 2010

• Computer Science Departmental Award, 2007 and 2010.

### **PROJECTS**

### Billings Commuter Challenge (www.billingscommuterchallenge.com)

The Billings Commuter Challenge volunteer project I built for the city of Billings. Every year, the city runs a friendly competition to show off the city's biking, walking, and bus infrastructure. The web app allows users can create profiles, join teams, log their trips and allows administrators to plan events, incentives, and view reports. It is built with Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Bulma CSS framework and is deployed using Capistrano to a Digital Ocean droplet running an nginx server.

#### **SKILLS**

Java | JavaScript | TypeScript | Vue | Vite | C | T-SQL | Linux | Mercurial | Git | Data Structures | Object Oriented Programming | Databases | Design Patterns | Perl